All right. In lesson one,
we figured out how to work with remote repositories.
In lesson two, we looked at how to start developing on a shared repository.
Now, let's look at how to sync our new changes back to
our forked remote repository and how to
retrieve updates from the original source repository.
Some things we'll look at in this lesson are,
learning what a pull request is and how to make one,
retrieving updates that have been made in
the source repository and including them in our fork,
working with an active pull request,
squashing commits with git rebase and more.
Let's start out by looking what a pull request is and how to create one.