Let's say we have this GIT repository,
but we realized that these last few commits are all minor changes, like typo fixes.
It would make for a much cleaner GIT log,
if these commits can be combined to do just one commit.
We could run GIT rebase - i head till the three to
combine or squash the last three commits into one.
Remember that head points to the current location.
For us, were on the master branch,
so head points to master.
Head till the one is one before head,
and is the previous or parent commit to the one wrong.
Head till the two is two before head,
and is the grandparent commit.
Head till the three, you guessed it is three before head,
and is the great grandparent commit of the commit we're on.
Now we don't want to get rid of commit eight,
that head till the three points to.
But this is the GIT rebase command,
so we're using head till the three as
the base that the other commits will be placed on two.
This can be a little tricky,
so the easiest way to remember it,
is that if you want to squash,
let's say 17 commits,
just use that number- 17 in this example as the number,
so it will be head till the 17.
So running GIT rebase - i head till the three will take
the commit were on and the previous two and let's us squash them into one.
This creates a new commit sha,
and it moves the master branch to point to this new commit.
Notice though now, that no branch is pointing to the original permits,
so they won't appear in a GIT log,
and GIT will eventually completely erase them.
Now if you're worried about damaging your repository and want a backup, well,
then creating a backup is actually what you've got to do. Let's start over for a second.
When I rebase, I just create a branch conveniently called backup,
that I place at the same location as the branch I'm rebasing.
I'm still on master, so I haven't checked out
the backup branch and I'll just run the same command.
This squashes the commits into one,
and moves master to point to this new commit,
but the original commits haven't been deleted and will still appear and get log,
because a branch is pointing at them.