This is the familiar starting point that we're used to,
where our local repository is behind the remote repository.
Now, let's pretend we didn't realize we were behind
the remote repository and made a commit in our local repo.
So now we have two repositories that have
the first same few commits but their master branches are pointing at different things.
If we tried running git pull right now, it wouldn't work.
But we know that we can use git fetch
to just retrieve the remote commits without merging.
So if we run git fetch origin master,
that will bring down the commits on
the remote repository and it'll make origin/master point to them.
Since we're on our master branch,
we can just run git merge origin/master
to bring the remote changes into our master branch.
Now our local repository has commits but the remote one doesn't have,
so we need to push them.
A quick git push origin master will update the remote repository with our local commits.