This is the sample git repository we built up in the previous lesson.
There are just a number of commits in the repository,
and there's a tag on one of the commits.
In addition to the tag, there's also a branch.
It's been hidden all this time, but let's show it.
By default, the first branch name is "master" but that's not a special name.
It's just the default name that's provided by git.
Now here's the cool part.
When a commit is made in the repository it's added to
the branch and the branch pointer moves to point to it.
Pretty neat, right?
If you remember, a tag is a permanent pointer to a commit,
and it doesn't move, but a branch does move when a new commit is added.
Let's add another branch to the repository and call it "sidebar".
Now, why would we want to do this?
Well, branches are incredibly powerful because they let us
work on the same project in different isolated environments.
Hold tight for a second and we'll see how this works.
A question you might be asking is,
"If we make a commit now,
which branch will move?
Will it be "master" or "sidebar"?"
Well, there's another hidden thing we need to reveal.
It's the oddly named "head" pointer,
and it points to the branch that's active.
Right now it's pointing to the "master" branch,
so "master" is the active branch.
We can use the checkout command to switch which branch it's pointing to.
To switch to the "sidebar" branch,
we'd use the command "git checkout sidebar".
Let's switch back with "git checkout master. "
If we make a commit right now,
the commit is added to the branch that "head" points to
because "head" indicates the current or active branch.
Let's switch over to the "sidebar" branch and add a commit there.
Now that "head" points to "sidebar,
" making commits now will add them to the "sidebar" branch.
Not only can we have as many branches as we want,
but we can choose where it starts from.
Let's say there's a problem with our header that was introduced back on commit a.
We can create a new branch right there with the branch command,
switch to it with the checkout command,
and make the necessary changes to fix the problem.
There's one quick but very important thing that I need to point out.
Let's switch back to the "master" branch for a second and make a commit.
The word "master" here indicates the tip of the branch,
but this most recent commit is connected to past commits.
The red line indicates all of the commits that are in the "master" branch.
So the commits 7 and b are not included in the "master" branch,
and the commits f and 4 are not in the "master" branch either.
So if we open up our code editor right now,
the changes that we made on commits f, 4, 7,
and b will not appear in any of the files
because git is only showing changes that are in the "master" branch.
Don't worry though. These commits are stored safely in the repository.
To get those commits out of the repository,
we just need to switch to the branch that has the commits we're looking for.
For example, if we switch to the header-fix branch,
the commits that are included on that branch will now
appear in the computer's file system and in the code editor.